Inventory of the Indian Petroleum Corporation records, 1926-1948
University of Wyoming. American Heritage Center.
Indian Petroleum Corporation records
1926-1948
Indian Petroleum Corporation, 1926-
01014
4.05 cubic ft. (9 document boxes)
University of Wyoming. American Heritage Center.
Articles of incorporation and by-laws; prospecting reports, drilling agreements, and oil and gas leases from fields in California, New Mexico, Texas, Montana, and Wyoming; correspondence regarding leases and sale of stock; and stockholders materials and Board of Directors minutes of meetings for Indian Petroleum Corporation.
History of the Indian Petroleum Corporation
The Indian Petroleum Corporation was founded in Carson City, Nevada, in 1926.
Scope and Content
The Indian Petroleum Corporation records contain articles of incorporation and by-laws; prospecting reports, drilling agreements, and oil and gas leases from the Corporation’s fields in California, New Mexico, Texas, Montana, and Wyoming; Corporation President C.M. Bowen’s and Secretary Lawrence E. Armstrong’s correspondence regarding leases and sale of stock; and stockholders materials and Board of Directors minutes of meetings.
Access Restrictions
There are no access restrictions on the materials for research purposes, and the collection is open to the public.
Related Materials
There are no other known archival collections created by the Indian Petroleum Corporation at the date of processing.
Acquisition Information
The American Heritage Center received the Indian Petroleum Corporation’s Records in 1961 from Ruel Armstrong of Rawlins, Wyoming.
Access Terms
Bowen, C. M.; Armstrong, Lawrence E.;; Oil and gas leases--West (U.S.); Oil fields--West (U.S.); Petroleum prospecting--West (U.S.); Petroleum industry and trade--West (U.S.); West (U.S.)--History.; Wyoming--History--1919-1945.; Business records.
Agriculture and Natural Resources; Mines and Mineral Resources; Business, Industry, Labor, and Commerce; Businesses and Corporations; Energy Production; Wyoming
Container List
- Armstrong, L.E.: Cheyenne Permit Exchange (for land in Carbon County), 1935-1938 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Armstrong, M.E.:
  - Ferris Field (Carbon County, Wyoming) Permit, 1926-1947 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Miscellaneous, 1926-1938 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Baggs Structure (Carbon County, Wyoming), 1931-1940 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Bakers Field (Kern County, California), 1928 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Board of Directors and Stockholders Materials, 1926-1929, 1940-1942 (Box 1, Folders 6-8)
- Bowen, C.M.: Sand Draw Field (Fremont County, Wyoming), 1920-1939 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- California Properties:
  - Rincon Point (Ventura County), 1929-1933 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Wellington Oil Company, 1929 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Carlson Permit (Lea County, New Mexico), 1926-1938 (Box 2, Folders 1-6)
- Carlson Permit (Lea County, New Mexico), 1939-1940 (Box 3, Folders 1-2)
- Cheesebrough, Arthur, 1931 (Box 3, Folder 3)
- Correspondence, 1927-1933 (Box 3, Folders 4-8)
- Correspondence, 1934-1945 (Box 4, Folders 1-7)
- Deputy, George W.: Permit (Lea County, New Mexico), 1926-1930 (Box 4, Folder 8)
- Engraving Plate of L.E. Armstrong, undated (Box 4, Folder 9)
- Ferris Field (Carbon County, Wyoming), 1927-1940 (Box 4, Folder 10)
- General Petroleum Corporation, 1927 (Box 5, Folder 1)
- Good, E.R. and Nutting, H.L., 1929-1932 (Box 5, Folder 2)
- Hiawatha Dome (Sweetwater County, Wyoming), 1926-1932 (Box 5, Folder 3)
- H.O. Dome (Carbon County, Wyoming), 1932-1934 (Box 5, Folder 4)
- Jeraco Development Company and Producers and Refiners Corporation, 1929-1931 (Box 5, Folder 5)
- Jeraco Development Company: State of Wyoming Lease, 1931-1940 (Box 5, Folder 6)
- Marland Production Company, 1929-1932 (Box 5, Folders 7-8)
- Miller Hill Structure (Carbon County, Wyoming), 1928-1929 (Box 5, Folder 9)
- Montana Properties, 1939 (Box 6, Folder 1)
- Montrose Structure (Montrose County, Colorado), 1927 (Box 6, Folder 2)
- New Mexico Applications and Permits, 1927-1929 (Box 6, Folder 3)
- Overland Structure (Carbon County, Wyoming), 1933-1937 (Box 6, Folder 4)
- Producers and Refiners Corporation, 1928-1932 (Box 6, Folder 5)
- Sholes, M.F.: New Mexico Lease, 1928-1937 (Box 6, Folders 6-9)
- Sinclair Refining Company, 1928 (Box 6, Folder 10)
- South Ferris Field (Carbon County, Wyoming), 1934-1937 (Box 6, Folder 11)
- Stewart, W.S.: New Mexico Lease, 1927-1934 (Box 7, Folder 1)
- Stock Transfers, 1929-1939 (Box 7, Folder 2)
- Sundin, Ernest: Estate, 1936-1948 (Box 7, Folders 3-4)
- Taylor Oil Company, 1932-1937 (Box 7, Folder 5)
- Texas Properties:
  - General, 1929-1930 (Box 8, Folders 1-2)
  - Williams, Joseph A., 1928 (Box 8, Folder 3)
- Thompson Lease (Lance Creek, Wyoming), 1930-1936 (Box 8, Folders 4-5)
- Wells, E.J.: New Mexico Lease, 1927-1934 (Box 8, Folders 6-8)
- Wells, E.J.: New Mexico Lease, 1935-1940 (Box 9, Folders 1-5)
- Westates Petroleum Corporation, 1940-1941 (Box 9, Folder 6)